Sina Salehi

sina.it@gmail.com (443) 862-0395

I have been building web applications using various languages and technologies for almost 8 years. I am currently working as a software engineer at QGenda. In my spare time, I have been working with graph databases, solving algorithmic puzzles and reading about new technologies. I am looking for a position in an agile environment within a small team of developers.

LinkedIn Sina Github sns Stackoverflow Sina

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT	HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, JQuery, NodeJS, React, Redux
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES	C#, Python, JAVA, C++, Erlang
DATABASE	MySQL, MS SQL Server, TitanDB, OrientDB
PROCESS	Agile, CI, TDD
OTHER TECH	Git, Mercurial, Apache, IIS, JBoss, Spring, Rexster, Vagrant, PubSub, Sphinx, REST, SPARQL, RDF, Message Queue
OPERATING SYSTEMS	Microsoft Windows family, Linux, OSX

EXPERIENCE

QGenda

Software Engineer Aug 2016 - Present

Building an automated physician scheduling solution

- Using MVC/CQRS architecture, and technologies such as C# .NET, react, redux, and SQL Server to build an automated scheduling platform for physicians
- Working on a scrum team and participating in all aspects of the development process
- Actively participating in architecture discussions and story breakdown/planning sessions.
- Developing new features and making modifications to existing features including but not limited to the core scheduling algorithm.
- Performing code reviews

DST Brokerage Solutions

Senior Software Developer May 2015 - Aug 2016

Worked on an application designed to replace paper forms, gather investment information, and determine if the potential investment is suitable. The product is used by fortune 500 investment companies.

- Designed and developed a compliance rule engine.
- Used technologies/tools such as Spring Framework, JBoss, Backbone.js, Handlebars.js, Junit

DST Converge

Software Developer Jun 2013 - May 2015

contributed to building and maintailing an enterprise social networking platform and CMS.

- Developed and maintained an internal self-hosted or SAAS-based social networking platform for 13.5k concurrent users.
- Implemented features such as user groups, file management, pre-post validations based on rule checking.
- Developed a platform to facilitate software development by outlining the software development lifecycle (S.D.L.C.), offer community question and answer forums, onboard associates, and schedule software product development.

Used graph database to built activity stream and notification system.

University Of Maryland Baltimore County

Research Assistant Sep 2012 - May 2014

- Researched on effective use of SVD (Singular Value Decomposition) in data feature reduction and feature selection
- Researched on Clustering The Normalized Compression Distance For Malwares Instances

Iran University of Science and Technology

Teaching Assistant Sep 2010 - Sep 2011

Teaching Assistant for courses "Computer Architecture" and "Web Programming"

■ Tutored students in web-development skills and technologies including PHP, Microsoft ASP.NET, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

EDUCATION

University of Maryland Baltimore County (UMBC)

Aug 2012 - May 2014

Masters of science - Computer Science

Iran University of Science and Technology

Aug 2007 - May 2012 Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering

LANGUAGES

English Fluent speaker

Persian

Native speaker